I was scared…
of this baby
that I brought into this world too soon.
And of myself
for having to make this decision.
I was scared of it all.
I couldn't bring myself to kill you.
So I abandoned you.
I thought I could move on.
Hyun-su!
But then I wanted to know…
why you were born this way.
Perhaps it was my fault
for not bearing you for long enough.
Or maybe it was my own filthy desires
that turned you into who you are.
What is my child?
Is she a gift or a curse?
I couldn't figure it out.
I thought…
you might have the answer.
I came too late, didn't I?
No.
I'm glad you're here.
Say hi.
She's your mom.
Hi.
You seemed perfectly normal.
What a relief that was.
Every single day I spent with you,
hiding my disquiet…
Every single ordinary day
that had me on thin ice…
I thought this life
might not be so bad.
I thought I had lost you.
But you suddenly stopped writhing in pain…
and stood before me
as a completely different being.
That's when I realized…
that no matter how much I denied it,
my child was a monster.
What's going on?
Do you have to go this far?
I'm her mom.
No matter how much she grows
or what she becomes,
I have to be able to recognize her.
I'll never lose her.
I don't know if I'm trying to
protect you from the world
or the world from you.
Don't ever take them off.
I'm just…
trying to be with you.
Okay?
ORIGINAL STORY WEBTOON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
SWEET HOME
Mom…
People…
They're all bad.
"Mom"?
You're just like them.
Cha Hyun-su.
Cha Hyun-su!
Are you really going to leave like this?
Did you expect a warm greeting?
Yes.
You should at least ask me how I've been.
I'm just not interested.
Was it you all along?
It was you who helped me
at the construction site, wasn't it?
You lead me on with this crap,
and now you're trying to run away?
Say something.
What?
Are you going to run away again?
Like an idiot?
I just happened to be there.
And I only helped you because I knew you.
You're alive.
Isn't that enough?
Do you have a death wish?
What the hell are you doing here,
you half-monster?
Get lost.
You idiot.
Even Ha-ni values her own life.
Why would you chase
a monster around, of all things?
Be thankful that you're alive.
Thank god.
He's been holding on.
He's alive.
If you're going to
mess around with monsters
and bring them to our shelter,
you can get lost too.
-Why did you do that?
-Because I don't like her.
And why not?
You keep hurting my friends
and vanishing because of her!
Because you want to protect her.
I don't trust you anymore.
At first…
I was curious about humans.
They're like Mom.
So I approached them…
but they only hurt me.
They screamed, pushed me away,
and hurt me.
They burned all my friends!
They force me to be alone.
They're just scared…
that they'll lose someone precious.
I'm going to do the same to them.
I'll make them pay for what they did.
It's your turn to feel what I felt.
Then you might finally understand…
my pain.
That's what I came to tell you.
Let's go home.
Please?
We have no home.
It's being burned down.
Now…
I don't need you
or Mom.
Yi-kyung!
Where are you?
Yi-kyung…
Hyun-su.
Yi-kyung, are you okay?
I ruined everything.
I wanted her to grow up to be like you.
That's all I wanted.
It's not your fault.
I should've killed her.
I always had that in mind raising her.
I'm sure…
she knew how I felt.
No.
I watched you raise her.
I saw how you endured everything.
It's all my fault.
I made all of this mess.
This is for the better.
Maybe it's best that I die here.
Then I won't have to…
kill her with my own hands.
Were you really going to kill her?
Why? You're her mom.
So why?
I don't deserve to be a mom.
I thought about it hundreds of times.
"Why was my child born this way?"
"It's my fault."
"My desires…
turned her…
into…
a monster."
What's wrong with that?
It's not a crime to be a monster.
Mommy…
This one protected you.
It considered you family.
Monsters can feel
and recognize faces too.
They were once human.
Mommy…
What's wrong with him?
Open your eyes.
What the hell are you doing?
I think he's dead, boss.
What's going on?
He was fine earlier. What happened?
He's been poisoned.
How much did you give him?
That much.
Just one bowl.
You gave all of that to him?
What the hell is this?
Poisonous mushrooms.
Ones that cause hallucinations.
She's got tolerance, so she's fine.
But he needs an antidote.
Hey!
Hey, wake up!
What a jerk.
How could he disappear again?
First, he hurts me
by enlisting without telling me.
And now he makes me cry
because of another girl?
PARK CHAN-YEONG
I'm done with him.
I'll take that if you don't want it.
Damn it.
Do you know how valuable this is?
There's a whole pile of them over there.
They're totally different.
Chan-yeong gave this to me
with his autograph.
You threw it,
so I thought you didn't want it.
So annoying.
-Are you ready?
-For what?
Are you going somewhere?
We're meeting
Father Peter today, remember?
I'm not in the mood for that.
Let's go. I don't want to go alone.
Let me come with you, Sarge.
No.
It's a personal matter.
How is Yong-seok a personal matter?
You're being too reckless.
Stop being so dramatic.
Report on my behalf tomorrow.
Tell him I'll be back with Yong-seok.
I can't do that, sir.
I'm sorry, Sarge.
I had to protect you.
I heard you got a signal from Bamseom.
Yes, sir.
Will you be okay on your own?
Take some of them with you.
What made you suddenly change your mind?
We're going the same way,
so let me join you.
I don't care what you think.
Just focus on coming back alive.
I'm going too.
Yong-seok is my subordinate and my friend.
You should stay, Min.
Kim Yeong-hu.
Didn't you say we were all family?
Are you really going to leave me out?
Look, man.
Who's going to lead the men
if both of us get killed?
They need you here.
Seo-jin.
I'll bring him back.
Just trust me.
I do.
You were better than me at everything.
But I just get this feeling
that I have to go myself.
I can't sit around here
after sending you off.
Take me with you, Yeong-hu.
Here's the thing.
If something happened
to you guys or Yong-seok,
I'd be useless anyway.
No need to get all serious.
I'm going if you guys are.
I'll come with you.
Anyone else cringing?
Look at these goosebumps.
Let's get going!
Wait, I can't drive
with my hand all screwed up.
Come on, everyone.
I can't see anything
with these on at night.
Let's go.
Aren't you coming?
What's wrong? You're so quiet today.
I can't stand this.
-Let's have a drink.
-What?
Could you at least be discreet?
Just let me have this.
I'll pay you back.
Got any extras?
Sure, whatever.
So…
are you going to go out with her or not?
Stop it.
He's a priest, for crying out loud.
What? I'm not saying he should marry her.
He can still go on dates.
You've had enough.
Wait.
What's going on between you two?
Are you guys dating?
Are you playing with Seon-hwa?
You're drunk. Get out.
Men are all cowards.
That's why you're not getting any.
Any man would run away
if you acted that way.
What did you say, bitch?
Hey!
You don't know shit.
What do you know about love?
I thought I was turning into a monster.
I thought I was hearing things.
Don't say such a thing.
We recently had an incident.
Goodness.
I haven't heard
the sound of music for so long.
Father.
You're quite resourceful, aren't you?
It's not free.
You have to confess to drink this.
You didn't come to today's meeting.
Come on, don't be like that.
Couldn't you at least bring something?
What?
Greed can make you a monster, you know.
Sharing is caring.
Turning into a monster wouldn't be so bad.
You'd live longer.
You wouldn't be sick
or scared.
-Come on.
-True.
Then again, life here may be fucked up,
but I'm not alone.
I'd be happy as long as I'm not a monster.
I want nothing more than that.
I want to leave as soon as possible.
I have so many things
I want to show and teach,
but it's not easy to do here.
What about you, Father?
Tell us about yourself.
You never talk about yourself.
She's right.
Let's hear it.
My life isn't too different
from what it used to be.
I have nowhere to go back to.
I love it.
I love how the world is in ruins.
Everyone can get along
because we're all the same.
I'm not lonely anymore.
You were homeless, weren't you?
I'm rich.
Bullshit.
No rich person would say that.
Why would you love it now
when you lost everything?
Man, this is depressing.
Screw it.
I, Jung Ye-seul,
will lighten up the mood.
Come on.
All right!
I should change the sign.
You seem happy.
You may take it for granted
since you're out and about all the time
but try living underground for a year.
Everything will seem new.
Not everyone is like you.
People are usually afraid.
What's with the suitcase?
It's a secret box.
What's inside it?
Don't you know what "secret" means?
It's a secret
because I don't know what will be in it.
Stop!
No. Stop!
Oh, no.
No.
Stop!
What is it?
I have a stomachache.
We're almost there.
I think I have to go right now.
It won't take long.
-Hey, Jong-hyun!
-Yes, sir.
Follow him.
Damn it.
Why are you taking that with you?
I don't know what might be there.
Jong-hyun, are you still waiting?
He must've held it in for a long time.
What did he even eat?
Stay alert.
Of course, sir.
Movement up ahead.
Please prepare to cover.
Roger.
Seo-jin, do you have visual?
I don't see anything.
-Seok-chan, get ready.
-Yes, sir.
Don't touch it…
I wiped.
What's that?
-Ditch that thing.
-No.
Absolutely not.
Fuck.
Run!
This is so damn heavy!
God damn it.
Run!
-Don't take it out on the case.
-Fuck this shit.
-Take it out on me.
-I swear I'll kill you.
What the hell is in there?
I almost broke my shoulders.
Maybe you should've worked out more.
Are you hiding something?
I'm not hiding anything.
Check the bag, Jong-hyun.
Wait, don't touch it!
For fuck's sake.
I said we should throw it away!
Sergeant Min,
you get scared pretty easily.
It's dead anyway.
That's what I'm saying.
Why are you bagging a dead monster?
Are you opening a monster museum?
-I've never seen this one before.
-Damn it.
Did you notice anything different
about those monsters back there?
Monsters don't recognize each other.
They have never teamed up
and gone after a single target.
-But this time?
-He's right.
It was as if they were all waiting for us.
They were working together.
Are you saying
they were trying to ambush us?
Or maybe they were
trying to protect something.
God damn it.
What's that?
It's bitter, but keep chewing on it.
I'm not eating it.
I'm not eating anything you give me.
Take him somewhere else.
He'll be dead soon.
Is this an antidote?
You have to tell me what it is
before I give it to him.
You think I'd give a dying man
something inedible?
Chew it.
Shut up and chew.
Let's go.
It's been exactly a year.
Wait up.
It's only been a year.
This is hardly an island anymore.
Nature is adapting to this disaster.
What do you mean, sir?
With humans out of the way,
it's going back to the way it was.
Clear.
-Seok-chan.
-Yes, sir.
Does that help?
I need something to lean on.
We'll be okay, right?
Why ask me?
Ask the one you believe in.
That's why I'm asking you.
Shut up, you idiot.
You're with me, Dr. Lim.
Seok-chan, on me.
Yes, sir. Of course.
I thought we were all staying together.
I'm kind of scared.
I've got sins to pay for.
Seo-jin, take the rest
and look for Yong-seok.
Okay.
Let's join up once we're done.
Hey, Seo-jin.
Try to come back in one piece.
Go.
Where do we go?
To my sector.
Research facility?
Are you a good fighter, Sergeant Kim?
You good at killing monsters?
You better be.
I'm not sure what's in there either.
Let's go.
It's the same drawing every time.
Yes. It's my house.
When will they send us home?
I want to go home.
Later.
Not now, but later.
How long do I have to wait?
You can't go home.
Yeong-su.
It's all a lie.
What if we become monsters
like Jun-il's mom?
Bad boy, Yeong-su.
You shouldn't be a good person either.
You might end up dying.
-Kim Yeong-su.
-Don't touch me!
Who are you to scold me?
You're not even my real mom!
Why do you keep that brat with you?
I'm already at my limit.
Don't get on my nerves.
I don't think there's anything over there.
You think?
I just hope some monster
doesn't show up out of nowhere.
-What do you mean?
-Don't you know?
You could break a ceiling down
looking for an ant colony.
Even a small house has surprises,
and this place is huge.
Who knows what could be here?
Come on, you're exaggerating.
We'll get a little extra something
if we work hard.
Are you going too?
Might as well.
My ass.
You don't have to
do these things, Ye-seul.
Why do the extra work?
Chief Ji takes care of you.
I'm just trying to do my part.
I should do something
if I don't want to disgrace my mom.
Your heart is as beautiful as your looks.
Look, old man.
I'm not an old man.
I'm not that much older than you.
Do you know how old I am?
Well…
Do you like me?
I can't say I don't.
Everyone here likes you, Ye-seul.
Guess what?
I don't like you.
You're not my type.
Even if the world came to an end,
you wouldn't be an option.
Jeez.
What was that?
Ye-seul.
I need your help.
You're the only one I can trust.
Please?
You got a signal from the search team?
Yes, they seem to have
safely arrived at Bamseom.
Can we get them on the radio?
No, sir. They're quite far.
If you get another signal,
report it immediately.
Yes, sir.
What's wrong with this thing?
What is it?
Something's disrupting the signal.
I'm sure!
I'm certain I heard it.
I heard a monster
behind the wall.
You can talk to Master Sergeant Tak.
Okay.
Sir.
It seems like…
there's a monster in the stadium.
Sir.
Look.
-We're detecting a monster.
-What the hell?
What's going on?
Emergency roll call.
Please follow us to the central plaza.
I'll be there soon.
You have to go right now.
Master Sergeant Tak wants you there.
Did he find an exit?
No.
We think there's a monster
inside the stadium.
All of those monster detectors
were beeping all at once.
This one's for real.
-Did you see it for yourself?
-Is he serious?
If it weren't for me,
you would be all dead.
-Is that so?
-Goodness!
-What a relief!
-Great job!
I can't stand that old man.
Tell me about it.
Why are you by yourself?
Did you ditch your family?
Did you?
I'm different.
We just had an argument.
You cheeky little brat.
After a little growing up,
I realized it was all my fault.
When grown-ups get mad at you,
it's for a good reason.
So go apologize to your mom.
My mom is already dead.
What was that?
Who says you can only have one mom?
You could have two or even three.
Ms. Cha is your mom, okay?
Little brat.
What's going on?
-Is there really a monster?
-Kill it already!
The Platoon needs to do their job.
What the hell are you doing?
The Crow Platoon will take care
of the monsterization incident today.
No one is safe.
That's the nature of this catastrophe.
We had to witness our friends, family,
and lovers' deaths
with our own eyes
and will continue to do so.
Do not trust anyone.
That's the only way
we can protect this place.
Don't stand around asking for protection.
Fight fiercely for your own lives.
If you don't brace yourselves,
you'll be consumed.
From now on,
those who hide their symptoms
and the ones who harbor them
will face immediate consequences.
Please help us
keep our hands clean.
What on earth is he talking about?
I think he means
they'll kill anyone with symptoms.
He just declared a reign of terror.
But the detectors were ringing!
Is he saying they took care of it or not?
We're safe, right?
I'm sure they dealt with it.
Great speech.
But didn't you forget something?
Stop hiding behind your men
and set an example for everyone.
Sir, you don't have to do this.
-What?
-What's going on?
-What's with the light?
-What is this?
Why did the lights turn off?
-What's going on?
-What the hell?
I can't just wait around.
-Is this the right place?
-Probably.
Aren't you going to ask
what I'm looking for?
Don't you want to know?
Is this about your research?
I don't need to know anything
that's not about the mission.
Our priority is to secure your item
and get out as soon as possible.
If it's that important…
someone might've taken it already.
No one can find it.
I have it hidden very well.
You sound so certain.
Of course.
What I'm looking for…
isn't an object.
The stench alone could kill us.
Something's here.
U-seok.
U-seok!
God damn it.
Motherfuckers.
From this point on,
kill everything in your sight.
What happened…
to this place?
Doctor, you can't go off on your…
Yeong-hu.
They got U-seok.
Seo-jin, what's going on?
Sergeant Min, report in.
Sergeant Min!
U-seok.
What are you doing here?
Hey, pull yourself together.
U-seok, answer me.
Hey.
Wake up.
Answer me.
Answer me!
U-seok.
Sir, we have to go.
Sir!
He's dead, sir.
We have to go now!
He's dead!
We gotta go, sir!
Let's go, U-seok.
Get your shit together, Sarge!
We have to go!
U-seok…
-Come on.
-U-seok.
-Come on already!
U-seok.
Sergeant Min.
Answer me, Min!
Seok-chan, tell them…
What the hell are these?
They were monsters.
But they've evolved.
Are you saying…
those are all monsters?
Don't touch it.
Did you forget about earlier?
You want me to pretend I didn't see this?
Why would I do that?
Don't do anything
that could sabotage the mission.
Sergeant Kim.
This is how the world works.
In order to gain one thing,
you have to be ready to lose another.
But you know that already, don't you?
Isn't that how you survived for so long?
If you're saying I should
be ready to lose my men,
I can't guarantee the safety
of your life either.
So you just want me to stare at it?
It's hanging right there.
To the research facility.
Something wrong, sir?
I think the guys are in trouble.
I can't reach them or ensure their safety.
Let's rendezvous with them.
-Let's go.
-After we came all the way here?
I can't.
No way.
I can't go back empty-handed.
What do you expect us to do then?
Will you stay here by yourself?
Fine.
What I'm saying is…
you should go ahead since I'd be a burden.
I'll be outside
after I tend to my business here.
-It'll be dangerous.
-It's fine.
Well, go already.
Your men could be in danger.
Okay then.
Let's roll.
Don't touch anything else.
Just find what you need and come back.
Understood?
Okay.
I get scared easily,
so I won't do anything rash. Just go.
Let's move.
I'm fine.
No, you're going to trip.
Sit by the fire.
So which is it?
Brother? Boss? Dad?
What's your real identity?
What's it to you?
Just eat this and get lost.
Why don't you come to the stadium with us?
You'll be safer there.
Am I getting married to you then?
No, ma'am.
"Safer"? You've just been lucky.
Or you're just ignorant.
We're doing a better job
than you might think.
I don't trust people.
Or monsters.
What about her? Do you trust her?
I guess you do.
Come on, let's go with them.
Please?
How dare you come here?
Help me.
This was the only place I could think of.
What happened to her?
What about the kid?
The little girl who was with you.
Let's get her inside.
Give me a hand.
Okay.
Sir!
You got some nerve, coming down here.
Stop it.
That's enough!
I warned you
not to bring in any monsters.
She's been looking for them.
-You should talk to--
-Does he look human to you?
Don't move an inch.
If you take another step,
It'll be her life.
This is why I don't trust people.
Look at how you repay me for saving you.
I said I'll take them away.
So what's the problem?
You're dangerous enough
for hanging out with monsters.
People should stick with people.
Are you confident?
That you won't become a monster?
You could start having symptoms right now.
Then you'd have to kill yourself.
Since monsters deserve to die.
That's enough.
What about her?
You should kill her if she turns.
Or would you rather
I kill her before then?
Let's just call it bad blood.
Stop it.
Don't do this, Eun-yu.
Ha-ni!
Let's go, old man.
Come on, let's go.
I guess we're not
meant to be in this life.
See you in the next one.
Don't bring her with you though.
Can you move?
What about the wound?
I'm fine.
We should get to safety.
The gunfire may have attracted monsters.
Let's go.
Hypocrite.
Coward.
Are you going to say
you had no choice again?
You were just running away.
You keep making the wrong decisions.
-Dad!
-You said you'd protect them.
Dad!
DAD
HELP ME
Help me!
But look at what you're doing.
I'm scared.
Tell everyone.
Dad!
Tell them that you're the monster
inside this stadium.
Sir.
May I come in?
We have a problem.
Sir?
Subtitle translation by Jea-heon Chung
Modify by Blue-Bird™